blubrry.com 2019-12-10

# Blubrry Podcasting Privacy Policy - Blubrry Podcasting - Podcast Hosting, Statistics, WordPress Hosting, Syndication Tools and Directory

The following RawVoice Inc., Blubrry Podcasting Privacy Policy went into effect on May 25, 2018.

RawVoice (parent company of Blubrry) is committed to protecting your privacy. We use the limited amount of information collected about you to enable the functionality of the Websites or to maintain you as a customer. These functions include letting you log in, setting up an account, purchasing products offered by Rawvoice/Blubrry and keeping you notified of news and changes to the Websites and Services. The Company may use personally identifiable information about you to improve our service, to statistically analyze site usage, to improve our content and product offerings and to customize our site’s content and layout. We believe these uses allow us to develop our website and better tailor it to meet our users’ needs.

**The Company will not sell, rent or give away any personally identifiable information about you to any third party whose use of that data will extend beyond the business purposes of Rawvoice/Blubrry. On occasion, we will aggregate personally identifiable information and may disclose such information in aggregate to third parties. However, in these situations, we will never disclose any information that could be used to identify you.**

## Information We Collect

_Information You Provide to Us_

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we receive information when you set up an account at RawVoice/Blubrry. We obtain this information so we can provide services to you. The types of information we collect may include personal information, which is information that can be used to identify you such as your _name, email address, mailing address, postal code, country, or telephone number_. This information is essential to allow us to provide services to you.

_Information We Collect Automatically_

In addition to the information you submit to us, we automatically collect specific information about your use of our Sites. This information may include unique device identifiers, Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses, browser characteristics, language preferences, operating system details, referring URLs, length of visits, and pages viewed. We may use tools such as cookies, web beacons, embedded scripts, web server logs, or other similar technologies to collect details about the services and devices you use to access the sites.

**Cookies:** A cookie is a unique identifier that is placed and stored on a computer when it is used to visit a website. Cookies may be used for various purposes, including to track user preferences or web pages visited while using a site, to identify the unique number of visitors to a website, and to verify whether or not a visitor is a repeat visitor.

**Web Beacons (“Tracking Pixels”):** Web beacons are small graphic images, also known as “Internet tags” or “clear gifs” that may be embedded in web pages and email messages. Web beacons may be used to monitor the number of visitors to a website, to track how users navigate a site, or to count the number of emails opened or specific pages or links viewed.

**Embedded Scripts:** An embedded script is programming code designed to collect information about a user’s interactions with a website. Typically, the script is temporarily downloaded onto a computer from the host website’s server (or the server of a third-party service provider) and is active only while the visitor is connected to the site, then deleted or deactivated after that.

_Data Analytics_

The Sites may use third-party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, to help us analyze how visitors use the Sites. These services track information about visitors including IP addresses, browser types, referring pages, pages visited, and time spent on particular pages which we use to improve our products and tailor the user experience on our Sites. To learn more about how Google may use information collected through the Sites, [click here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). For information on how to opt out of data collection through Google Analytics, [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Your web browser may have settings that allow you to transmit a “Do Not Track” signal when you visit various websites or use online services. Like many websites, the Sites are not designed to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from browsers. To learn more about “Do Not Track” signals you may wish to visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com/](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

Third parties who have no relationship with Rawvoice/Blubrry may collect personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you visit our Sites. Rawvoice/Blubrry has no control over these activities, and the collection of this data may be the result of cookies, placed by these third parties, on your computer.

## How We Use Your Information

We may use the information we obtain through the Sites for several purposes including:

  * _Unique device identifiers, web cookies_ : To improve the Sites and to personalize our visitor’ experiences on the Sites;
  * _Name, email, country, postal code_ : To provide a personalized account login;
  * _Name, email_ : To respond to emails or other requests, comments, or questions;
  * _Name, email, telephone  number_: To provide customer support;
  * _Email_ : To provide you with information that we believe may be useful to you, such as information about products or services we offer;
  * _Mailing address_ : To comply with applicable laws, regulations, or legal process as well as industry standards and our company policies;
  * _IP address_ : To prevent fraud or other misuses, including by protecting our rights and the rights of affiliates or related third parties;
  * _Name, email_ : To maintain records of our transactions and communications;
  * _Unique device identifiers, web cookies_ :  To monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities of visitors to the Sites; or
  * Other personally identifiable information for any other purpose with your consent.

Also, we may use the information we obtain about you in other ways for which we provide notice at the time of collection.

## How We Share Your Information

We may share the information we collect with our agents, vendors, consultants, and other third parties performing services on our behalf, for example, to help us develop, operate, maintain, improve, and protect our products and services. These third parties may only use your information to carry out the functions for which they have been engaged and in accordance with this Policy.

We may also disclose your information (1) if we reasonably believe that we are required to do so to comply with applicable law, regulation, or legal process (such as in response to a court order or subpoena); (2) to fulfill requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities; (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (4) to enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we obtain through the Sites in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a merger, reorganization, or liquidation).

## Security

We maintain appropriate physical, electronic and administrative safeguards designed to protect personal information that we obtain in accordance with this Policy. Although we use reasonable efforts to secure such information, transmission via the Internet is not entirely secure, and we cannot guarantee the confidentiality of information transmitted to us over the Internet.

## Links to Other Websites

The Sites may contain hyperlinks to other websites or online locations for your convenience and information. Those linked websites may have their own privacy policies or notices and operated by unaffiliated entities. This Policy does not apply to those websites so please review the privacy policies posted on those sites to understand how they may collect and use your personal information. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of websites we do not control.

## Social Features

The Sites include features that are designed to permit interactions that you initiate between the Sites and third-party websites or services, including their party social networks (“Social Features”). Examples of Social Features include enabling you to “like” or “share” our content or your content on other websites or services or to transmit content to our Sites from your account on a third-party website or service.

If you choose to use Social Features on the Sites, both Rawvoice/Blubrry and the third party may have access to specific information about you and your use of both the Sites and the third-party site or service. Also, we may receive information about you if other users of a third-party website allow us to access their profiles and you are one of their “connections” or if information about you is otherwise accessible through those individuals’ profiles or pages on a social networking or other third party website or interactive service.

The information we collect in connection with Social Features is subject to this Privacy Policy. The data collected and stored by the third parties remain subject to those third parties’ privacy practices including whether the third parties continue to share information with us, the types of information shared and your choices about what is visible to others on those third-party websites or services. 

## Children’s Privacy

The Sites are not intended for children, nor is it targeted to children under the age of thirteen (13). We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 through the Sites, and if we learn that we have received information from a visitor under the age of 13, we will delete such information in accordance with applicable law.

## California Privacy Rights

California law permits customers in California to request specific details about how their information is shared with third parties and, in some cases, affiliates for direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business must either provide this information or permit California customers to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing. We do not share personal information with third party affiliates for those third parties’ or affiliates’ direct marketing purposes. California customers may request information about our compliance with this by contacting us at [privacy@rawvoice.com](mailto:privacy@rawvoice.com), or by postal mail at 5000 Arlington Centre Blvd., Bldg. 2, Upper Arlington, Ohio 43220. Any such inquiry must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the subject area of your email or the first line of your postal mail inquiry. You must also include your name, street address, city, state and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email address.

Any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use the Sites and who have posted content or information on our Sites may request that such information be removed from the Site by contacting us at [privacy@rawvoice.com](mailto:privacy@rawvoice.com) and stating that they posted such content or information and detailing where the content or information is displayed. We will make reasonable good faith efforts to remove the post or content from prospective public view or anonymize it to protect the minor’s identity. This removal process cannot ensure complete or comprehensive removal.

## Information for Users Outside the United States

Rawvoice is located in the United States, and U.S. law governs the information we collect. If you are visiting the Sites from outside the United States, please be aware that information we collect through the Sites will be transferred to, and processed in, the United States. By using the Sites, you acknowledge and consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States as described in this Policy. The data protection laws and regulations applicable to your personal data transferred to the United States may be different from the laws in your country of residence. 

## Your Choices

You may request that we update, correct or delete your information collected through the Sites by emailing [privacy@rawvoice.com](mailto:privacy@rawvoice.com). To help protect your privacy and security, we may take reasonable steps to verify your identity before honoring any such requests.

You may delete your account by [signing in](https://www.blubrry.com/signin.php), then from the _Podcaster Dashboard_ select “Account Settings” > “Delete Account”.

Many web browsers provide options to allow you to stop accepting new cookies or to disable existing cookies. Go to the HELP function of your browser to learn how. You can also go to [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for information about how to disable and control cookies on most browsers. Please be aware that if you disable the cookies on your computer, you may not be able to use specific features of our Sites or other websites. Disabling cookies may invalidate opt-outs that rely on cookies to function. Also, these options may not be useful in all cases or may be valid concerning one type of browser or service but not another.

You may unsubscribe from receiving promotional emails from us by following the instructions provided in those email communications. Please note that even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications from us, we may continue to send you non-promotional emails such as emails concerning our ongoing business relationship with you. 

## English Language Controls

This policy is executed in English and may be translated into other languages. In the event of any conflict or discrepancy between the English language and a translated version of the English language version shall control to the fullest extent permitted by applicable law.

## Changes to this Policy

We may change this policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of this Policy. We encourage you to review this Policy whenever you visit the Sites to stay informed about our information practices.

## Contact Us

To contact us regarding this Policy or with questions about our privacy practices you may use our [contact form](https://www.blubrry.com/contact/), email us at [privacy@blubrry.com](mailto:privacy@rawvoice.com) (please include “Privacy Inquiry” in the subject line of your email) or call us at 1-877-729-8642, or send postal mail to:

Blubrry Podcasting  
Attn: ONLINE PRIVACY INQUIRY  
150 East Campus View Blvd.  
Suite 180  
Columbus, Ohio 43235  
USA

### About Blubrry Podcasting
